{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The symptoms of retinol excess are", "opta": "bone fragility", "optb": "nausea", "optc": "weakness", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Main function of insulin hormone is to", "opta": "increase glycogen in liver", "optb": "decrease glycogen in liver", "optc": "increase blood sugar", "optd": "decrease blood sugar", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ascorbic acid acts as an", "opta": "reducing agent", "optb": "oxidizing agent", "optc": "oxidizing and reducing agent both", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A deficiency of thiamin produces the disease known as", "opta": "beri-beri", "optb": "scurvy", "optc": "cataract", "optd": "anemia", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Acyl carrier protein (ACP) plays an important role in the biosynthesis of", "opta": "fatty acids", "optb": "amino acids", "optc": "sugars", "optd": "carbohydrates", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vitamin B12 (Cobalamin) is only synthesized by", "opta": "fishes", "optb": "micro-organisms", "optc": "plants", "optd": "animals", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following are reduced coenzymes?", "opta": "NADH and FADH2", "optb": "NAD+ and FAD", "optc": "ATP and GTP", "optd": "Coenzyme A and ubiquinone", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The absence of ascorbic acid in the human diet gives rise to", "opta": "rickets", "optb": "pernicious anemia", "optc": "cataract", "optd": "beri-beri", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vitamins are essential because the organism", "opta": "can't synthesize these compounds at all", "optb": "can synthesize these compounds partially", "optc": "can't synthesize these compounds in the adequate amounts", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The prosthetic group biotin is a carrier of which type of molecule?", "opta": "Activated carbon dioxide (CO2)", "optb": "Ammonia", "optc": "Methyl group", "optd": "Sulfhydryl group", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lipoic acid exists in", "opta": "oxidized form", "optb": "reduced form", "optc": "oxidized and reduced form both", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vitamin B12 is useful in the prevention and treatment of", "opta": "pernicious anemia", "optb": "scurvy", "optc": "cataract", "optd": "beri-beri", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An example of a digestive hormone is", "opta": "lipase", "optb": "pepsin", "optc": "amylase", "optd": "gastrin", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the co-enzyme B12the position occupied by a cyanide ion in vitamin B12 is bonded directly to the __________ of the ribose of adenosine.", "opta": "adenine", "optb": "5-6 dimethylbenzimidazole", "optc": "hydroxycobalamin", "optd": "cyanocobalamin", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The reductant, NADH, transfers the electrons via a flavo-proteins to the specific disulfide (S-S) protein to form a dithiol (SH,SH) protein which converts vitamin", "opta": "B12(Co2+)to B12(Co)", "optb": "B12(Co) to B12(Co2+)", "optc": "B12(Co2+)to B12(Co+)", "optd": "B12(Co+)to B12(Co2+)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An early sign of retinol deficiencies in man is", "opta": "night blindness", "optb": "keratinization", "optc": "xeropthalmia", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An enzyme, L-folate reductase reduces folic acid to", "opta": "hydrofolic acid", "optb": "dihydrofolic acid", "optc": "trihydrofolic acid", "optd": "tetrahydrofolic acid", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What compound of raw egg white causes a syndrome similar to vitamin B deficiency?", "opta": "Avidin", "optb": "Betabindin", "optc": "Ovalbumin", "optd": "Albumin", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The disease Beriberi is due to a dietary deficiency in", "opta": "vitamin B1 (thiamine)", "optb": "vitamin B2 (riboflavin)", "optc": "vitamin B6 (pyridoxine)", "optd": "vitamin B12", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of these is a symptom of vitamin A deficiency?", "opta": "Osteoporosis", "optb": "Impaired taste perception", "optc": "Blindness", "optd": "Impaired blood clotting", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vitamin-C is considered as a", "opta": "water soluble", "optb": "fat soluble", "optc": "fat and water soluble", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The vitamin niacin is part of the __________ molecule.", "opta": "ferredoxin", "optb": "pyridoxal phosphate", "optc": "pyrophosphate", "optd": "NAD+", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of these hormones is a catecholamine?", "opta": "Follitropin", "optb": "Norepinephrine", "optc": "Tetraiodothyronine", "optd": "Tetrahydrofolate", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Dihydroorotate dehydrogenase contains", "opta": "4 flavins and 4 atoms of iron per molecule", "optb": "2 flavins and 4 atoms of iron per molecule", "optc": "2 flavins and 2 atoms of iron per molecule", "optd": "4 flavins and 2 atoms of iron per molecule", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "E.coli ACP has its molecular weight as around", "opta": "9000", "optb": "19000", "optc": "39000", "optd": "90,000", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The vitamin riboflavin is part of the __________ molecule.", "opta": "ferredoxin", "optb": "FAD", "optc": "pyridoxal phosphat", "optd": "pyrophosphate", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most prominent role that tocopherol has in in-vitro systems is as a strong", "opta": "antioxidants", "optb": "reducing agent", "optc": "oxidizing agent", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Biotin occurs mainly in combined forms bound to protein through", "opta": "\u03b5-N-lysine moiety", "optb": "\u03b5-S-lysine moiety", "optc": "\u03b5-N-biotinyl-L-lysine", "optd": "\u03b5-N-lipoyl - L-lysine", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lipoic acid is a co-factor of the", "opta": "pyruvic dehydrogenase", "optb": "\u03b1-ketoglutaric dehydrogenase", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "di-hydroorotate dehydrogenase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\u03b2-carotene together with \u03b1-carotene, \u03b3-carotene and cryptoxanthine are synthesized by", "opta": "plants", "optb": "animal", "optc": "plants and animals both", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vitamin-D deficiency can cause", "opta": "rickets", "optb": "pernicious anemia", "optc": "cataract", "optd": "beri-beri", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A deficiency of Vitamin K results in a decreased level of", "opta": "prothrombin", "optb": "thrombin", "optc": "fibrin", "optd": "fibrinogen", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The vitamin riboflavin, which occurs as a yellow pigment in egg yolk and milk become", "opta": "colorless on reduction with Zn in acid and regained its color on re-oxidation", "optb": "colorless on oxidation and regained its color on reduction with Zn in acid", "optc": "more deep in color on reduction with Zn in acid and regained its color on re-oxidation", "optd": "more deep in color on oxidation and regained its color on reduction with Zn in acid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following compounds/(s) belong/(s) to the vitamin B6 group?", "opta": "Pyridoxal", "optb": "Pyridoxine", "optc": "Pyridoxamine", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What metal ion is specifically bound by vitamin B12?", "opta": "Cobalt", "optb": "Copper", "optc": "Zinc", "optd": "Iron", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A fat-soluble vitamin that regulates blood clotting is", "opta": "vitamin A", "optb": "vitamin K", "optc": "vitamin C", "optd": "niacin", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of these is a vitamin A precursor?", "opta": "Cobalamin", "optb": "Pyridoxine", "optc": "Beta-Carotene", "optd": "Thiamine", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In one  iron-metalloflavoprotein, the iron is present as a", "opta": "heme-protein", "optb": "nonheme type", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "flavin moiety", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vitamin K1 was first isolated from alfalalfa and has the phytyl side chain consisting of", "opta": "four isoprene units", "optb": "six isoprene units", "optc": "nine isoprene units", "optd": "four isoprene units", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of these molecules is vitamin H?", "opta": "Biotin", "optb": "Carnitine", "optc": "Folic acid", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The occurrence of metals such as iron or molybdenum in some flavoproteins can", "opta": "stabilize the semiquinone", "optb": "de-stabilize the semiquinone", "optc": "form chelation", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Models of end-linked Osaka VI Fibrinogen dimers, a bilayer dimer is linked at", "opta": "both ends by one disulfide bond", "optb": "either end via two disulfide bonds", "optc": "either end via a single disulfide bond", "optd": "both ends by two disulfide bonds", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A deficiency of niacin causes", "opta": "pellagra", "optb": "scurvy", "optc": "cataract", "optd": "anemia", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Selenium is an essential component of the enzyme glutathione peroxidase which", "opta": "scavenges toxic hydoperoxycompounds in tissues", "optb": "reduces toxic hydoperoxycompounds in tissues", "optc": "oxidizes toxic hydoperoxycompounds in tissues", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Who discovered vitamin C (ascorbic acid)?", "opta": "Paul Berg", "optb": "Linus Pauling", "optc": "Albert Szent-Gyorgyi", "optd": "Kerry Mull is", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}